

PH.D. CANDIDATE · COMPUTATIONAL CHEMIST

101 Smith Hall, Pleasant St SE, Minneapolis, MN 55455, USA

□ (+1) 612-231-6989 | ■ pqh3.14@gmail.com | ♣ hungpham2017.github.io | • hungpham2017 | □ hung-pham-4b46598b

"Think differently."

Summary.

I am a Research Assistant at the University of Minnesota, Twin Cities. I am interested in developing new numerical techniques for periodic systems and strongly correlated materials. I have been working on variety of projects from electronic structure method developments to their applications to condensed phases. These helped me earning skills and expertise in the fields of quantum embedding theories, wave function theories, density functional theory, crystallography, photovotaics, and crystalline porous materials.

Education

University of Minnesota, Twin Cities

Ph.D. in Chemistry, Advisor: Laura Gagliardi

Minneapolis, MN 55455, USA

2015 - 2020

VNUHCM-US (Vietnam National University Ho Chi Minh City - University of Science)

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

Nov 2017 - Present

B.S. IN CHEMISTRY, HONOR PROGRAM

2007 - 2011

Experience

University of Minnesota

Minneapolis, MN 55455, USA

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

- Developed density matrix embedding theory for strongly correlated materials
- In silico design of lead-free perovskites for optoelectronic applications
- Theoretical study of light absorption and emission in the iridium complexes for OLED applications.

TEACHING ASSISTANT Sep 2015 - Dec 2016

• Courses: General Chemistry laboratories: CHEM 1017, CHEM 1065, CHEM 1066.

Center for Molecular and NanoArchitecture (MANAR)

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

Oct 2011 - Jul 2015

Oct 2011 - Jul 2015

- Investigated gas adsorption in metal-organic frameworks, zeolite imidazole framework.
- Modeling and topological analysis in crystalline framework materials.

Institute for Computational Science and Technology (ICST)

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

• Investigated the band-gap engineering in metal-organic frameworks.

VNUHCM-US Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Oct 2011 - Jul 2015

 $\bullet \ \ \text{Courses: General Chemistry laboratory, Physical Chemistry laboratory, Computational Chemistry laboratory.}$

Skills_

Programming

- Python, C/C++, Fortran90
- Git, ŁTEX

Softwares

- PySCF, VASP, CRYSTAL, Gaussian
- Crystal Maker, Materials Studio

Coding Projects

pDMET (https://github.com/hungpham2017/pDMET)

DESCRIPTION

• A package to compute electronic structure of periodic systems and materials by means of density matrix embedding theory.

MCU (https://github.com/hungpham2017/mcu)

DESCRIPTION

• A Python package to analyze the periodic wave functions from DFT calculations.

pyWannier90 (https://github.com/hungpham2017/pyWannier90)

DESCRIPTION

• A Python interface for wannier90 used to construct the maximally-localized Wannier functions.

Publications

- 1. **H. Q. Pham**, M. R. Hermes, L. Gagliardi; *Periodic Density Matrix Embedding Theory: A Wave Function Approach for Strongly Correlated Materials*, **J. Chem. Theory Comput.**, 2019, ASAP. %
- 2. R. Sanner, N. Cherepy, **H. Q. Pham**, V. Young; *Phosphorescent Heteroleptic Iridium (III) Cyclometallates: Improved Syntheses of Acetylace-tonate Complexes and Quantum Chemical Studies of Their Excited State Properties*, **Polyhedron**, 2020, 176, 114256.
- 3. **H. Q. Pham***, D. Q. Le, N.-N. Pham-Tran, Y. Kawazoe, D. Nguyen-Manh; *Electron Delocalization in Single-Layer Phthalocyanine-Based Covalent Organic Frameworks: A First Principle Study*, **RSC Advances**, 2019, 9, 29440. %
- 4. R. Sanner, N. Cherepy, H. P. Martinez, H. Q. Pham, V. Young; Highly Efficient Phosphorescence From Cyclometallated Iridium(III) Compounds: Improved Syntheses of Picolinate Complexes and Quantum Chemical Studies of Their Electronic Structures, Inorganica Chim. Acta, 2019, 496, 119040.
- 5. **H. Q. Pham**, R. J. Holmes, E. S. Aydil, L. Gagliardi; *Lead-Free Double Perovskites Cs*₂*InCuCl*₆ and (CH₃NH₃)₂*InCuCl*₆: Electronic, Optical, and Electrical Properties, Nanoscale, 2019, 11, 11173. %
- 6. **H. Q. Pham**, V. Bernales, L. Gagliardi; Can Density Matrix Embedding Theory with the Complete Active Space Self-Consistent Field Solver Describe Single and Double Bond Breaking in Molecular Systems?, **J. Chem. Theory Comput.**, 2018, 14, 1960. %
- 7. D. Ray, C. Clarke, **H. Q. Pham**, J. Borycz; T. Zhang, E. S. Aydil, R. J. Holmes, L. Gagliardi; *A Computational Study of Structural and Electronic Properties of Lead-Free CsMI*₃ *Perovskites (M = Ge, Sn, Pb, Mg, Ca, Sr, Ba)*, **J. Phys. Chem. C**, 2018, 122, 7838.
- 8. P. T. K. Nguyen, H. T. D. Nguyen, **H. Q. Pham**, J. Kim, K. E. Cordova, H. Furukawa; *Synthesis and Selective CO*₂ *Capture Properties of a Series of Hexatopic Linker-Based Metal-Organic Frameworks*, **Inorg. Chem.**, 2015, 54 (20), 10065.
- 9. T. L. H. Doan, H. L. Nguyen, **H. Q. Pham**, N.-N. Pham-Tran, T. N. Le, K. E. Cordova; *Tailoring the Optical Absorption of Water-Stable Zr^{IV-} and Hf^{IV-}-Based Metal-Organic Framework Photocatalysts*, **Chem. Asian J.**, 2015, 10, 2660. %
- 10. **H. Q. Pham**, T. Mai, N.-N. Pham-Tran, Y. Kawazoe, H. Mizuseki, D. Nguyen-Manh; *Engineering of Band Gap in Metal–Organic Frameworks by Functionalizing Organic Linker: A Systematic Density Functional Theory Investigation*, **J. Phys. Chem. C**, 2014, 118 (9), 4567.

Presentations.

The 4th International Workshop on Nanotechnology and Application - IWNA

Vung Tau, Vietnam

ORAL

• Engineering of Band Gap in Metal-Organic Frameworks by Functionalizing Organic Linker.

Nov. 2013

Chimie et Matériaux Avancés pour Environnement - CMAE2015

Hanoi, Vietnam Jun. 2015

ORAL

• Engineering of Band Gap in Crystalline Framework Materials via Functionalizing Organic Linker.

MolSSI Workshop for Python Simulation Software

Pasadena, CA, USA

• Multiconfigurational Wave Function Methods for Periodic Systems via Density Matrix Embedding Theory.

256th ACS National Meeting

Boston, MA, USA

Aug. 2018

ORAL

· Multiconfigurational Wave Function Methods for Periodic Systems via Density Matrix Embedding Theory.

APS March Meeting 2019 Boston, MA, USA

ORAL

• Density Matrix Embedding Theory for Strongly Correlated Solids.

The 3th International Workshop on Nanotechnology and Application - IWNA

Vung Tau, Vietnam

Mar. 2019

Nov. 2011

Aug. 2016

Oct. 2017

Jul. 2017

• Mixed-linker based zeolitic imidazolate frameworks: Solvothermal synthesis and Computer simulation.

2016 All-Hands Meeting and Reaction Mechanisms Workshop

St. Paul, MN, USA

Poster

• Metal exchange in the zirconia node of NU-1000 for catalysis.

Minneapolis, MN, USA

Minnesota Supercomputing Research Exhibition 2017

Poster

• Metal exchange in the zirconia node of NU-1000 for catalysis.

Minnesota Workshop on ab initio Modeling in Solid State Chemistry with Crystal 2017

Minneapolis, MN, USA

POSTER

• A Novel Double Perovskite Cs2InCuCl6: First-principles Study on Electronic, Optical, and Electrical Transport Properties.

Service to the community_

Reviewing activities

- Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation, ACS %
- Solid State Communications, Elsevier %

Honors & Awards

Vietnam Education Foundation (VEF) Fellowship, VEF (declined)

Vietnam

2008 Lawrence S. Ting Scholarship, Lawrence Ting Memorial Fund Vietnam

2008-2011 Academic Excellent Scholarship, VNUHCM-US

Vietnam

Referees_

Laura Gagliardi

McKnight Presidential Endowed Chair, Distinguished McKnight University Professor, Director INORGANOMETALLIC CATALYST DESIGN CENTER

· University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN 55455, USA

Christopher J. Cramer

VICE PRESIDENT FOR RESEARCH, DISTINGUISHED MCKNIGHT UNIVERSITY PROFESSOR

• University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN 55455, USA